

MID, Yucatán, México rnovelo.cruz98@gmail.com (+52) 999-9090-601 in/rnoveloc github/rnovec

### Education

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering Instituto Tecnológico de Mérida / TecNM

AUG. 2017 TO 2021

Programming Technician Specialty - High School CBTIS No. 80 / DGETI 2014 TO 2017

### Certifications

- Python Knowledge
- React + Redux
- Vue.js Profressional
- Node.js con Hapi

## Languages

- Spanish (Native)
- English (Intermediate)

# Raúl Novelo Cruz

## BackEnd Software Engineer

## **Summary**

Experienced Fullstack Developer with 3+ years of broad experience in the areas of Backend, Frontend, Cloud and DevOps. Also, I am community leader, open-source collaborator, and author for technical articles. Among the strengths I have developed are my excellent communication skills, teamwork, critical thinking, creativity, and problem-solving.

## **Work Experience**

**Lighthouse Technologies,** Back End Developer (full-time)
JAN 2022 - PRESENT

- Coordinating with development teams to determine application requirements.
- Writing scalable code using Python and Django REST framework.
- Testing and debugging applications.
- Developing back-end components.
- Integrating user-facing elements using server-side logic.

### ParamQ, Freelance (part-time)

JAN 2021 - DEC 2021 (1 year)

• Fullstack Developer (Python/Django and Vue.js)

**AAAIMX**, Former Leader (part-time)

APR 2019 - APR 2021 (2 years)

- Founder and leader of Software Division
- Project advisor and BackEnd developer
- Design and maintenance oficial website and admin
- Implementing microservices and REST architecture
- Speaker, teacher and advisor in projects for DSC

### **Skills**

Programming Languages	Frameworks	Databases and Tools
Python	Django	PostgreSQL
JavaScript	Django REST Framework	MySQL
HTML/CSS	Vue.js / Vuex	MongoDB
Java	Node.js / Express / Socket.IO	Celery
C/C++	Docker / Git / Github	RabbitMQ